远鉴字幕组制作
[Visionary] 0day-sub
敦刻尔克 中英双语字幕：william2568 & Zcc911
DUNKIRK
受敌方压制 英法联军撤至海边
THE ENEMY HAVE DRIVEN THE BRITISH AND FRENCH ARMIES
TO THE SEA
"你们已被包围"
"WE SURROUND YOU"
困于敦刻尔克 等候命运降临
TRAPPED AT DUNKIRK, THEY AWAIT THEIR FATE
祈求奇迹出现
HOPING FOR DELIVERANCE
以逃出重围
FOR A MIRACLE
英国人! 我是英国人! 英国人!
English! I'm English!
走吧 英国佬 快溜吧
Allez, Anglais. Bon voyage.
这里是掷弹兵团 伙计
It's grenadiers, mate.
让开
Make way!
Out of the way!
走走走
Go, go, go!
沿着防波堤 一路走过去
Along the mole. All the way.
船就要开
The ship's about to leave.
沿着防波堤 一路走过去 船就要开了
Along the mole. All the way. The ship's about to leave.
陆 一周
1. THE MOLE
one week
我们的空军都死哪去了?!
Where's the bloody air force?
海 一天
2. THE SEA
one day
海军要征用这船
The navy's requisitioned her.
他们一小时内回来 父亲想在那之前准备妥当
They'll be back in an hour. My dad wants to be ready before then.
海军要我们清理船舱 给救生衣腾地方
They've told us to strip her and load those life jackets.
有些人在对岸的敦刻尔克 他们需要这船
Some men across the Channel, at Dunkirk, need taking off.
有些人?
Some men?
空 一小时
3. THE AIR
one hour
检查燃油 福蒂斯小队1号 2号
Check fuel, Fortis 1 and 2.
70加仑(318升)
70 gallons.
68加仑(309升) 福蒂斯长机
68 gallons, Fortis Leader.
高度降至500英尺(152米) 节省燃料
Stay down at 500 feet to leave fuel
准备在敦刻尔克上空战斗40分钟
for 40-minute fighting time over Dunkirk.
明白 航向128 高度500英尺(152米)
Understood. Vector 128, angels point five.
随时注意仪表读数
And keep an eye on that gauge, even when it gets lively.
预留充足返航燃料
Save enough to get back.
不收法军 不收法军
No French soldiers. No French soldiers. No.
不不 不收法国人 只向英国人开放 只收英军!
No, no French. English only. English only past this point.
不 这艘是英国船 你们会有自己的
No. It's a British ship. No, you have your own ships.
退后! 退后!
Get back. Get back.
你们的船会到的 这是英国船
No, you've got your own ships. This is a British ship.
退后!
No, get back.
把担架抬过来 有担架来了
Look, get the stretchers through. There are stretchers coming.
让开来! 别挡道!
Get out of the way! Out of the way!
沿着防波堤 一路走过去
Go, go, go. Along the mole. All the way.
船快要开了 快开了
The ship's about to leave. About to leave.
沿着防波堤 一路走过去
Along the mole. All the way.
沿着防波堤 一路过去
Along the mole. Along the mole. All the way. All the way.
不行
No.
只收英国人! 只收英国人!
No, English only. English only!
不行
No!
船艉已就绪!
Ready on the stern!
是 长官
Yes, sir!
升起船帆!
Man the bowline!
还有位置吗?
Any more room?
退回去! 退回去!
You have to get back!
只剩两分钟
That's two minutes.
你们已经错过了 错过了
You've missed it. You've missed it.
这是最后一个了吗?
Is that the last one?
是 长官
Aye, sir.
解掉船缆!
Break the line.
出发! 出发!
Come on! Come on!
敦刻尔克太远了 怎么不到加来(法国)上船?
Dunkirk's so far. Why can't they just load at Calais?
敌人可不答应
The enemy had something to say about it.
从这出发 他们可就成活靶子了
Ah, down here we're sitting ducks.
保持警惕 敌机会在太阳方位出现
Keep 'em peeled. They'll come out of the sun.
排队
Up the line.
嘿 交给我们 ...
Oi. We'll take it.
收起跳板!
Drop the gangplank!
是 长官
Yes, sir!
试着走过来!
Take a run at it.
把艉缆收好 乔治
Ready on the stern line, George.
不等海军的人了吗?
Aren't you waiting on the navy?
他们要征用"月光宝石"号 那就给他们吧
They've asked for the Moonstone, they'll have her.
船长跟着船走
And her captain.
他儿子也去
And his son.
谢谢你来帮忙 乔治
Thanks for the help, George.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
你知道我们去哪吗?
You do know where we're going?
去法国
France.
是去参战 乔治
Into war, George.
我会帮上忙的 先生
I'll be useful, sir.
敌机 8点钟方向
Bandit, 11 o'clock.
散开
Break.
他咬住我了
He's on me.
我对付他
I'm on him.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8...
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight...
你俩 赶紧回去!
Oi, you two.
上岸归队!
Get a shift on.
把这拉紧了 打个结
Yeah, pull him tight. Tie a knot in it.
你们两个 退后
Back up the line. Both of you.
可以走了!
Off you go.
Off you go!
上次轰炸把船舵给弄坏了!
That last barrage has damaged the rudder.
呃 ... 好的
Uh, okay...
道森先生!
Mr. Dawson!
咱们的飞机 乔治
One of ours, George.
福蒂斯2号 听我口令 诱他到左舷
On my mark, Fortis 2. Draw him left.
3, 2, 1
Three, two, one.
机动
Mark.
搞定
Clear.
他坠机了吗?
Is he down?
对 他完蛋了
Yeah, he's down for the count.
福蒂斯长机 击落敌机一架
Fortis Leader, one bandit down.
福蒂斯长机 收到了吗?
Fortis Leader, do you read?
福蒂斯2号 你在我左舷 但我看不到长机 完毕
Fortis 2, I have you to my port. I have no eyes on Fortis Leader. Over.
明白 福蒂斯1号
Understood, Fortis 1.
绕圈搜寻 ...
Orbit for a look.
还要多久 上尉?
How long, Lieutenant?
得换新缆绳 长官 旧的缠得厉害
We need to run a new cable, sir. They're scrambling.
去吧
Very well.
上校 你得下决定了 还要撤离多少伤员 ...
Colonel, you're gonna have to decide how many more wounded to evacuate.
一副担架就得挤掉7个人的位置
One stretcher takes the space of seven standing men.
对不起
Excuse me.
- 少将 - 中校
- Rear Admiral. - Commander.
防线如何?
How's the perimeter?
每天都在收缩
Shrinking every day.
不过后卫部队和法军 都还在坚守阵地
But between our rear guard and the French, we're holding the line.
还有 敌人的坦克停下来了
And the enemy tanks have stopped.
为什么?
Why have they stopped?
光靠空袭就够了 咱们已经是瓮中之鳖
Waste precious tanks
何必再耗费宝贵的坦克?
when they can pick us off from the air, like fish in a barrel?
在达成协议前 伦敦方面 还要我们守多久?
How long does London expect the army to hold out before we make terms?
达成协议?
Make terms?
德国人不会善罢甘休的 我们得把军队撤回去
They're not stopping here. We need to get our army back.
敌人下一步就是英国 然后就是称霸世界
Britain's next and then the rest of the world.
老天 ...
Christ.
在这几乎都能望见了 ...
I mean, you can practically see it from here.
什么?
What?
家
Home.
法国人怎么办?
What about the French?
台面上 丘吉尔说要"手挽着手"
Publicly, Churchill's told them, "Bras dessous."
携手并肩 不离不弃
Arm in arm, leaving together.
私下呢？
And privately?
让咱们的人撤回来
We need our army back.
要撤多少人 长官?
How many men are they talking about, sir?
丘吉尔的计划是3万人 拉姆齐中将希望能撤4万5千人
Churchill wants 30,000. Ramsay's hoping we can give him 45.
这海滩上可挤了40万人 长官
There are 400,000 men on this beach, sir.
大家都尽力吧
We'll just have to do our best.
没错 要不惜一切代价 让防波堤保持畅通
Right, well, this mole stays open at all costs.
我们处在西侧敌人的炮火范围内 要是这儿有东西沉了
We're in artillery range from the west. If anything else sinks here,
就会堵瘫整个防波堤
the mole's blocked and we're stuffed.
不能到海滩上装船吗?
Can't we load from the beaches?
总比呆这儿挨炸要强
Better than standing out here when the dive bombs come.
- 不可能的 - 水太浅吗?
- It's impossible. - Too shallow?
吃水超过3英尺(0.9米) 船就进不来
'Cause anything that drafts over three feet can't get near.
我们的划桨船也不够 没法把人分批送上驱逐舰
We don't have enough small boats to ferry men to the destroyers.
那么先生们 全靠防波堤了
The mole it is, then, gentlemen.
嘿
Hey!
嘿! 你能游过来吗?
Hey! Can you swim it?
能不能再近点?
Dad, can you get closer?
别冒险!
Can't risk it!
坚持住
Hang on.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
下面有残骸
Wreckage below.
109战机吗?
Is it more of the 109?
不
No.
是福蒂斯长机 完毕
It's Fortis Leader. Over.
他逃出来没?
You think he got out?
我没见到降落伞
I didn't see a 'chute.
记录长机坐标
Record his position.
转至128航向 高度 ...
Then set heading 128,
1000英尺(305米) 完毕
height 1,000. Over.
航向128 高度1000英尺(305米) 明白
Vector 128, angels one. Understood.
福蒂斯2号 燃油状况?
Fortis 2, what's your fuel?
50加仑(189升) 完毕
50 gallons. Over.
50加仑(189升)
50 gallons.
好的 保持提醒
All right, keep letting me know.
我的仪表刚才被打坏了
My gauge took a bit of a knock back there.
你要不要返航?
Shouldn't you turn back?
不用
No, no.
相信只是仪表出了问题
I'm fairly confident it's just the gauge.
- 船要沉了! - 砍掉缆绳!
- She's going down! - Cut her loose!
伤员们怎么办?
What about the wounded?
全体弃船 弃船!
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
砍掉缆绳 把船挪走!
Cut her loose, and push her off!
别让船沉在这儿!
We can't let her sink at the mole!
推下去!
Push the bloody boat off!
救命!
Help us!
你要不要下来?
Do you want to come below?
里头更暖和
It's much warmer.
甲板上风大
It's out of the wind.
喝点吧
Here you go.
别管他 乔治
Leave him be, George.
呆在甲板上 他觉得更安全
He feels safer on deck.
你被炸了也会有同感
You would too if you'd been bombed.
U型潜艇
U-boat.
是U型潜艇
It was a U-boat.
再给他倒杯茶 乔治
Get him some more tea, George.
好了 我们还有5分钟航程
Right, we're about five minutes out,
爬升至2000英尺(610米) 完毕
so climb to 2,000. Over.
那样更费油吧
That's more fuel.
现在我可不想遭遇敌机
I know, but I don't want to get jumped again.
咱们先爬升上去
Let's get a decent altitude.
然后再俯冲作战 完毕
We can dive down on the bastards from above. Over.
明白 二号
Understood. Angels two.
完毕
Over.
好了 高地兵
Right, Highlanders.
再给你们找艘船吧
Let's find you another ship.
快点
Come on.
所有人 继续爬 爬到甲板上
Everyone else, keep climbing. Climb on the deck.
爬到甲板上
Climb on the deck.
小心! 小心别碰到头了!
Watch your heads on the rail. Watch it.
往下走 拿上毯子
That's right, keep going down. Take a blanket.
从这儿往下走 披上这个 亲爱的
Down you go. Put this on, my love.
往下走 一直往下走
Down you go. Keep going down.
底下给你们准备了热茶
There's a nice cup of tea for you down there.
一直往下走
Keep moving down.
裹上毯子
Take a blanket.
好了 挪一挪
Try and make some room.
往下走 小伙子们
Keep moving down, boys.
走这边
This way.
这里有茶可供饮用
A cup of tea down there.
这边 请往下走!
There you go. Down there. Move down there.
你朋友怎么了?
What's wrong with your friend?
他在找逃生捷径
He's looking for a quick way out.
万一船沉了 就派上用场了
In case we go down.
我们要去哪儿?
Where are we going?
敦刻尔克
Dunkirk.
不 不 我知道 是回英格兰!
No, uh, no, no, we're going to England.
我们得先去敦刻尔克
We have to go to Dunkirk first.
我不要回去!
Look, I'm not going back.
我不要回去 ...
I'm not going back.
你瞧瞧!
Look at it.
如果我们 ... 我们去了就死定了!
If we go there, we'll die.
我明白你的意思了 年轻人
I see your point, son.
咱们绘个航线吧
Well, let's plot a course.
你先下去喝喝茶 暖暖身子
You can take your tea below and warm up.
彼得 给他找个地方休息下
Peter, have we got space for a man to lie down?
好的
Uh, yeah.
这里 来吧
Here, come on.
小心
Careful.
就这里
Just in there.
我去给你加点茶
I'll get you some more tea.
他是懦夫吗 道森先生?
Is he a coward, Mr. Dawson?
乔治 他患了炮弹休克症
He's shell-shocked, George.
现在神志不清
He's not himself.
搞不好一辈子都这样了
He may never be himself again.
喝吧
Here you are.
40加仑(151升) 福蒂斯1号
40 gallons, Fortis 1.
40加仑(151升) 明白
40 gallons, understood.
海因克尔轰炸机 11点钟方向
Heinkel, 11 o'clock.
它在轰炸队形里 目标是扫雷舰
She's lining up to drop her load on that minesweeper.
战斗机呢?
Fighters?
恩 都是109 在它右舷
Yeah, 109s off her starboard.
我负责轰炸机
I'm on the bomber.
打中了! 打中了!
Got him! Got him!
它转向了 肯定被你击中了
Oh, she's turning. You must've damaged her.
护卫机呢?
Where's the escort?
我击落一架 ...
Well, I got one of...
噢! 上帝!
Jesus!
我正在下坠
I'm going down.
我缠住他 你跳伞
I'm on him. Bail out.
海况良好 准备水上迫降
No, the swell looks good. I'm ditching.
别抛下我们
Don't leave us!
回来!
Come back!
- 等等我们! - 救命!
- Wait for us! - Help! Help us!
带我们走! 带我们走!
Pick us up! Pick us up!
回来!
Come back!
鱼雷!
Torpedo!
弃船!
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
救命!
Help!
把我们救出去!
Get us out of here!
喷火战斗机 乔治
Spitfires, George.
史上最棒的飞机
Greatest plane ever built.
你没看就知道啦
You didn't even look.
劳斯莱斯“梅林”发动机
Rolls-Royce Merlin engines.
这是战场上最悦耳的声音了
Sweetest sound you could hear out here.
有人吗?!
Hello?
把门打开!
Could you open the door?
喂 能听到我吗?
Hello? Can you hear me?
快开门哪!
Open the door!
能听见我吗?!
Do you hear me?
他想出来
He wants to come out.
你干了什么? 把他锁里头?
What have you done? Locked him in?
让他出来 天呐!
Let him out, for God's sake.
有人吗?
Hello?
让我出去!
Let me out!
你们没有掉头!
You haven't turned around.
没有 我们有任务在身
No. We have a job to do.
任 ... 任务? 这 ... 这可是艘游艇!
Job? This is a pleasure yacht.
你们 ... 你们只是业余水手 又不是海军!
You're weekend sailors, not the bloody navy.
像你这把年纪的人 …
A man your age?
像我这把年纪的人 有些正在主导这场战争
Men my age dictate this war.
我们又凭什么 只让年轻人去战斗?
Why should we be allowed to send our children to fight it?
你就该待家里头!
You should be at home!
如果这场战争蔓延到英国 我也就无家可归了
Well, there won't be any home if we allow a slaughter across the Channel.
他掉头逃了 我去追他
He's turning tail. I'm gonna get after him.
祝好运
Good luck.
留意燃油 你还有15加仑(57升)
Watch your fuel. You're at 15 gallons.
15加仑(57升) 明白
15 gallons, understood.
祝你好运 柯林斯
Best of luck, Collins.
柯林斯 你没事吧?
Collins, do you read?
不! 不!
Oi! No! No!
一边去!
Get off! Get off!
滚开 船上太挤了!
Piss off, the both of you. It's too crowded.
你们不能撇下我们!
You can't leave us!
腾腾位子!
Make some room!
不! 不!
No!
一边去!
No! Get off!
你们快住手 船会翻掉的
You men, leave off. You'll capsize the boat.
来这的路上已经翻过两次了
She's gone over twice on the way out here.
冷静下来 船是够用的
You have to stay calm. There are plenty of boats.
冷静?!
Calm?
等你也被鱼雷炸了 再来扯这个吧!
Wait till you get torpedoed, then tell us to be calm!
你们有救生衣吗?
You have life jackets?
有 他们有的
Yes, they do.
你们不要慌 海水还算平静
Don't panic, boys. The water's not too rough
也不太冷
or too cold.
我们先回海滩上
We're heading back to the beach.
- 咱们去多佛(英国)吧! - 对!
- Let's go to Dover! - Yeah!
这船没法渡过海峡 伙计们
We can't make it across the Channel in this, lads.
我们得回到海滩上 等下一班船
We need to get back to the beach and wait for another ride.
水里的弟兄们 保持体力
You men in the water, float here, save your strength.
我们会回来接你们的
We'll come back for you.
提桨!
Oars in!
提桨! 划!
Together, pull!
提! 划!
划!
Pull!
提桨! 划!
Together, pull!
划!
Pull!
提! 划!
Together, pull!
这是躲不掉的 孩子
There's no hiding from this, son.
你以为你们能帮到什么?  就凭这玩意?
What is it you think you can do out there, on this thing?
我们不是孤军作战 号令下来了
There's not just us. A call went out.
大家都挺身而出
We aren't the only ones to answer, you know.
你们连枪都没有!
You don't even have guns.
你有枪吗?
Do you have a gun?
有 当然了! 来复步枪 303口径
Yes, of course. A rifle, a 303.
它能帮你回击俯冲轰炸机吗? U型潜艇呢?
Did it help you against the dive bombers and the U-boats?
你真是个老糊涂
You're an old fool.
我不会回去的!
I'm not going back.
不会回去的!
掉头返航!
Turn it around.
我们不会掉头的
I'm not turning round.
掉回去!
Turn it around!
让它掉 ...
Turn it...
- 冷静 老兄! - 掉头回去
- Calm it down, mate. - Turn it around!
冷静 冷静
Wait, wait!
冷静点 老兄!
Calm it down, mate.
乔治?
George?
乔治?!
George!
你都做了什么?
What have you done?
好的 你没事了 乔治
Okay, you're all right, George.
你没事的!
You're all right.
坚持住
Hang on. Okay. Okay, just...
好的 现在
That's it. That's good enough.
要给你压一下 好了
It's gonna keep some pressure on. There we go.
好了
There we go.
能听到我吗 乔治?
Can you hear me, George?
加把劲 伙计们
Come on, lads!
Come on! Come on, boys!
等到海水涨起来
It's a pier.
就把它当码头用
For when the water comes in.
现在在涨潮了
The tide's turning now.
你怎么知道?
How can you tell?
尸体都漂回来了
The bodies come back.
嘿!
Hey.
嘿! 高地兵们!
Hey, Highlanders!
那边是什么?
What's that way?
有艘船
A boat.
搁浅了
She's grounded.
等到涨潮后 就不是了
Not when the tide comes in, she's not.
挺住 兄弟
Be a brave lad.
遇见你和道森先生
You and Mr. Dawson?
是我做过最棒的事情
It's the best thing I've ever done.
你没事的 你很好
You're all right. You're okay.
参加海事青年团 那是我做过的唯一一件事了
Sea Cadet. It's the only thing I've ever done.
没事的 好了 喝口水吧
It's all right. It's okay. Just have some water.
我跟父亲说过
I told my dad...
我在学校里虽然一事无成
I've done nothing at school
可总有一天会混出点名堂
and that I would do something one day.
也许会登上本地报纸
Maybe get in the local paper.
也许老师们会读到我的报道
Maybe my teachers would see it.
好了 休息一下
Okay, get some rest.
等你恢复了 甲板上我还需要你
I need you back up on deck as soon as you're able.
做不到
I can't.
什么?
What?
我看不见了
I can't see.
长官
Sir.
西侧的法军已经被迫后撤了
The French have been forced back on the western side.
但原来的防线还在吧?
They're still holding a perimeter?
目前是的
For now.
给长官让路 都让让 让让!
Officer coming through. Move yourselves. Move yourselves!
驱逐舰在哪里?
Where are the destroyers?
很快会再来一艘
There'll be one soon.
一艘?
One?
经过昨天的损失 现在一次就来一艘了
After yesterday's losses, it's one ship on the mole at a time.
这就是战场
The battle is here.
他们藏着船究竟想做什么?
What the hell are they saving them for?
为了以后的战斗
The next battle.
为了保卫不列颠
The one for Britain.
飞机也一样
It's the same with the planes.
可英国近在眼前!
But it's right there.
你几乎可以看 ...
You can practically...
就算看得到 也不意味着你能平安返家 上尉
Seeing home doesn't help us get there, Colonel.
那边得增派更多船只
They need to send more ships.
敌人时刻都在逼近
Every hour the enemy pushes closer.
当局已经启用"小型运力池"来增援了
They've activated the small vessels pool.
"小型运力"
Small vessels?
也就是征召民船
It's the list of civilian boats for requisition.
民船?
Civilian?
我们要的是驱逐舰
We need destroyers.
小船可以到海滩上载人
Small boats can load from the beach.
但现在不合适
Not in these conditions.
比起俯冲轰炸 我宁愿它波浪滔天
Well, I'd rather face waves than dive bombers.
说的没错 这海况没法出航 ...
No, you're right. They won't get up in this.
皇家工兵团在用卡车搭建临时码头
The Royal Engineers are building piers from lorries.
起码在涨潮后能派上用场
At least that should help us when the tide comes back.
我们只有6个小时
Well, we'll know in six hours' time.
不是3小时一次涨潮吗?
I thought the tides were every three?
所以才说 你是陆军 我是海军 对吧?
Then it's good that you're army and I'm navy, isn't it?
那儿 "征服者"号驱逐舰 ...
There. Vanquisher.
船员去哪儿了?
Where's the crew?
可能是搁浅后害怕了
Probably got spooked after they ran aground.
逃到了海滩上
Scarpered up the beach.
为什么?
Why?
因为我们在防线外头 敌人可能就在附近
'Cause we're outside the perimeter. Enemy could be right there.
好的 咱们最好藏到里头 弟兄们!
All right, best shut ourselves inside, boys.
然后待到涨潮
Wait for the high tide.
那要多久?
How long's that?
3小时一次
Every three hours.
我用力压住了伤口
I've put a bit of pressure on it.
给他缠上了绷带 希望能他能舒服些
Strapped him up, made him comfortable.
什么?
What?
他情况很糟 爸爸
It's bad, Dad.
我们要不要掉头?
Well, should we turn back?
船都到这了
We've come so far.
那边是咱们的飞机吗?
Dad, is that one of ours?
那架是海因克尔轰炸机 他们要攻击那艘扫雷舰
That's a Heinkel. They'll go for that minesweeper there.
我们是不是要准备援救幸存者了?
Hang on. Shouldn't we stand by to pick up survivors?
先活下来再说吧
To do that we have to survive ourselves.
把头伸出去 看看涨潮了没
Poke your head out. See if the water's come in.
你不是很健谈么?
Talkative sod, aren't you?
几乎没有
It's barely come in at all.
- 他妈的! - 冷静点!
- Fuck's sake. - Calm down.
有退潮自然会有涨潮 不是么?
What goes out comes back in again, right?
对啊 但要等多久?
Yeah, but how long?
喷火战斗机!
Spitfires!
加油
Come on.
加油 加油
Come on, come on.
爸爸! 他打中了!
Dad, he got him!
好!
Yeah! Yeah!
轰炸机飞走了!
The Heinkel's moving off.
对!
Yeah.
噢 不
Oh, no.
那架喷火战斗机着火了!
Smoke from the Spitfire!
注意降落伞的位置!
Watch for a parachute!
- 你是德国人?
Are you German?
- 不 荷兰人! 我是荷兰人!
No, Dutch. Dutch!
我是商船队的
Merchant navy.
- 来接你们 来帮忙的
Here to pick you up. To help you.
- 干嘛要离开船?
Why'd you leave your boat?
我们担心德国人会过来
In case the Germans come.
我们在海滩上
We wait up the beach.
跟大家一起 等涨潮呢
With the soldiers. Wait for the tide.
你回来了 那肯定是涨潮了
You came back. The tide must be in.
对 涨了 ... 没错儿
Coming. Coming, yes.
但还得再等几个小时 船才能浮起来
But more hours till we float.
几个小时!
Hours?
那怎么现在就回来了?
Why'd you come back?
我走的时候船里可没这么多人啊!
Not so heavy when I left.
没有降落伞!
No 'chute!
祝你好运 柯林斯
Best of luck, Collins.
柯林斯 你还好吗?
Collins, do you read?
飞机坠毁了
He's down.
爸
Dad.
爸 看那引擎
Dad, watch the engine.
他完蛋了 他没有降落伞
Dad, he's down. There was no 'chute.
爸 别去了 他没降落伞
Dad, come on. There was no 'chute.
估计人已经死了
He's probably dead.
彼得 别说了 我听到了
Damn it, I hear you, Peter! I hear you!
说不定还活着呢 谁说得准
He may be alive. Maybe.
也许还能救他一命
We may be able to help him.
别乱来! 我们会暴露的
No! Then they'll know we're in here.
除了咱们 他们还能射谁?!
Why else are they shooting at us?
你们看那队形
Look at the grouping.
在练靶子而已
Target practice.
去 堵上它 快去
Go. Plug it. Go, go.
咱们得把洞堵上!
We have to plug it.
那你先请吧!
After you, mate.
怎么离开这儿?!
You ready? Go!
我们得扔掉些压舱物?!
How do we get off? Do we need to ditch some ballast?
太重了! 我们要减轻重量!
Weight! Do we need to lose weight?
减重 对
Weight. Weight, yes.
没错
Yes.
我们要送个人出去
Somebody needs to get off.
有人自愿么?
Well volunteered.
不必这样
We don't need a volunteer.
我知道谁该出去 ...
I know someone who ought to get off.
就是他
This one.
他是德国间谍
He's a German spy.
别瞎说
Don't be daft.
他是德国鬼子
He's a fucking Jerry.
你们有没有注意到他一直一言不发
Have you noticed he hasn't said a word?
我是注意到了
'Cause I have.
他根本就不会英语
He don't speak English.
就算会说 也带着一股浓浓的德国泡菜味
If he does it's with an accent that's thicker than sauerkraut sauce.
胡说八道 快回击他
You're daft. Tell him.
没错
Yeah.
尽管说吧
Tell me.
说啊 吉布森!
Tell me, Gibson.
说话!
Tell me!
我的天 说句话啊!
Tell him, for God's sake!
青蛙佬
A frog.
你个臭青蛙佬
A bloody frog.
插队的懦夫
A cowardly little queue-jumping frog.
吉布森又是谁 嗯?
Who's Gibson, eh?
肯定是沙滩上某个裸死的英国人
Some naked, dead Englishman lying out on that sand?
你扒完他的衣服 有没有把人安葬好?
Did you at least have the decency to bury him?
葬好了 我俩一块埋的 我以为那是他的战友
He did. I helped him. I thought it was his mate.
- 没准儿就是他杀的吉布森呢 - 他没杀那人
- Maybe he killed him. - He didn't kill him.
你又怎么知道?!
How do we know?
在这儿的海滩上找一具英国人尸体 能有多难?
How hard is it to find a dead Englishman on Dunkirk beach?
他没杀人
He didn't kill anyone.
他跟咱们一样 只想赶紧离开这鬼地方!
He was just looking for a way off the sand, like the rest of us.
那边枪还没练够吗?!
Haven't they had enough practice by now?
他们在确保船没法浮起来
They're trying to make sure she won't float.
这船还能浮起来?!
Will she still float?
浮起来 可以的 减轻重量就行了
Float, yes. Yes, with less weight.
最该赶谁出去 大家心里都清楚
And we know who's getting off.
不能那样 他是法国的盟友 自己人
No, you can't do that. He's French. He's on our side.
好啊 那你走吧
Go on. Up you go.
你把他赶出去 他就死定了
As soon as he pokes his head out, they'll slaughter him.
反正死的不是我
Better him than me.
这不公平
It's not fair.
保命要紧 扯啥公平
Survival's not fair.
说得对
No, it's shit.
都怕死 都贪生
It's fear, and it's greed.
那就以多服少
Fate pushed through the bowels of men.
妈的
Shit.
他救过大家的命
He saved our lives.
那他马上可以再救一次了!
And he's about to do it again.
不! 等一等!
No, don't! Stop!
必须得让个人下船 不然全都活不成
Somebody's gotta get off, so the rest of us can live.
你愿不愿意出去?
If you wanna volunteer...
没门儿
Fuck no.
我要回家
I'm going home.
如果这就是条件呢?
And if this is the price?
我可以接受
I'll live with it.
但这错得离谱
But it's wrong.
出去!
Go on!
就赶一个人出去 也没多大用
One man's not going to make enough difference.
你最好希望这招有用 不然下一个就轮到你了
You'd best hope it does, because you'd be volunteering next.
什么?
What?
伙计 大家都是战友
We're regimental brothers, mate.
就该有牺牲自己的觉悟
It's just the way it is.
浮起来了!
We float!
快启动发动机!
Start the bloody engine!
下午好
Afternoon.
抱歉 朋友 我 ... 我真的不知道
I'm sorry, son. I really don't know.
你做的对 不该挪动他
You're right not moving him.
你已经尽全力了
You've done the best for him you can.
我们白忙了一天
We've wasted the day.
我也很沮丧 上校
I share your frustration, Colonel.
约翰尼!
Johnny!
那艘搁浅的拖网渔船着火了
Grounded trawler, taking fire.
敌人从东侧沙丘带攻了过来
They're breaking through the dunes to the east.
守不住了
This is it.
堵住弹孔!
Plug the holes!
用什么堵
With what?
堵住弹孔!
Plug the holes!
那边 去那边堵住
Other side! Other side!
看到什么了?
What do you see?
家
Home.
他还好吧? 小伙?
Is he all right? The boy?
不
No.
他不好
No, he's not.
爸!
Dad!
加油 加油
Come on. Come on, Farrier. Come on.
那边有人在漂着
There's men in the water!
油
Oil.
油 浮油! 你要开进浮油里了!
It's oil. Oil. You're getting into oil!
继续往下走
Keep coming.
下面空间足够
Plenty of room.
好了 到下面去
All right, below deck.
- 弃船! - 弃船!
Abandon ship!
吉布森 快走
Gibson! Leave it!
到舱里吧
Below decks.
我们得让尽量多的人上船
Listen, we have to get as many of you on board as we can
不然浮油着火就全完了
before that oil catches fire.
你要么挪进舱去 要么就别待船上 自己选吧
You go below decks or you get off my boat. That's your choice.
后面的跟上
Keep coming.
小心! 小心! 别碰着他!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Careful! Careful down there!
Careful! Careful down there!
他死了 伙计
He's dead, mate.
那更不要动他!
So be bloody careful with him.
他能挺过去么?
Um, will he be okay?
那个年轻人?
The boy?
能的
Yeah.
飞机飞回来了
He's coming back round.
飞机飞回来了!
He's coming back round!
伙计 动作快点!
Come on, Farrier. Come on.
快跳船!
Get off the ship!
加油! 再打下一架
Come on, Farrier. Get around them.
加油!
Come on, come on.
快开船!
Go.
快! 快!
Go! Go! Go!
快! 快! 快!
Go!
慢点
Easy.
带我回家吧
Take me home.
你们是哪儿的?
Where are you from?
达特茅斯附近
Out of Dartmouth!
我的天
Christ.
从迪尔来的吗?
You from Deal?
是的
I am!
小心出口的水流!
You watch the current at the mouth!
好的
Aye.
谢谢你们!
And thank you!
有架敌机
That's a fighter.
嗯 一架ME-109 从南边飞来了
Yes, an Me 109.
彼得 你来掌舵
From the south. Peter, you take the tiller.
听我指令
Listen for my instructions.
往南开
Point her south!
全速前进 彼得
Full speed, Peter.
它一直在盘旋
Keep coming round.
要飞过来了
Keep coming.
它开火前肯定会降低高度 等我信号
Before he fires, he's gotta drop his nose. I'll give you the signal.
- 现在吗? - 不不 再等等 ...
- Now? - No, no. Wait.
等它开始瞄准了 ...
Wait for him to commit to his line.
就现在!
Now!
飞机坠毁了
He's gone.
是啊 掉海里喂鱼了
Yeah, bigger fish to fry.
你又怎么知道这些的?
How'd you know that stuff, anyway?
我儿子也是空军
My son's one of you lot.
我知道他会保佑咱们的
I knew he'd see us through.
你是皇家空军的?
You're RAF?
不 不是我
No. Not me.
是我兄弟 还开过飞机横穿飓风呢
My brother. He flew Hurricanes.
开战第三周就牺牲了
Died third week into the war.
麻烦待着 不要走动
No, stay downstairs, please.
我们只是想看看海崖
We just wanna see the cliffs.
- 那是多佛港么? - 不
- Is it Dover? - No.
那是多塞特港
That's Dorset.
终究是回家了
But it's home.
我们是不是让你们失望了?
We let you all down, didn't we?
我的天 你这船上装了多少人?
Christ, how many you got in there?
走到火车上去
Make your way to the trains.
大家参战 你又在哪!
Where the hell were you?
他们知道你的壮举
They know where you were.
再见
Bye.
喝茶吗?
Cup of tea?
喝杯茶吗?
干得漂亮
Well done. Well done.
干得漂亮!
Well done, lads.
干得漂亮 小伙子们
Well done. Well done, lads.
干得漂亮
Well done.
我们只是勉强活下来了而已
All we did is survive.
这就够了
That's enough.
干得漂亮
Well done.
干得漂亮!
那老家伙都不愿正眼瞧咱们
That old bloke wouldn't even look us in the eye.
快过来吧 列兵
Come on, private!
我知道军官优先 但不是敌死就是我亡
I know we're officers, but it's us or the enemy.
不是讲究这些时候
So now is not the time to be particular.
已经撤回3万人了
Well, Churchill got his 30,000.
那可不止
And then some.
快有30万人了
Almost 300,000.
到目前为止
So far.
目前为止?
So far?
我要留下来
I'm staying.
等法军
For the French.
嘿!
Hey!
我们到哪儿了?!
Where are we?
临时停靠 马上就开车了
Siding. You'll be pulling in in a minute.
到哪一站?
What station?
沃金站
Woking.
帮我拿份报纸吧
Grab me one of them papers.
快去啊!
Go on!
敦刻尔克：三十三万五千人获救!
丘吉尔在众议院发表关于敦刻尔克撤退的演讲
我不忍心读下去
Can't bear it.
你念出来吧
You read it.
不忍心?
Can't bear it?
要是他们没有锁起门来等着沦陷
They'll be spitting at us in the streets.
那就肯定是到街上朝咱啐唾沫了
If they're not locked up waiting for the invasion.
"战争从不是靠撤退取胜的"
"Wars are not won by evacuations."
我看不下去了
I can't look.
"但应当注意到
"But there was a victory inside this deliverance,"
这次救援却孕育了胜利"
"which should be noted."
"众多盟军士兵得以成功撤回 我们对此满怀喜悦"
"Our thankfulness at the escape of our army"
"但不能因此 就对目前在法国和比利时的盟军溃败
"must not blind us to the fact that what has happened"
视而不见"
"in France and Belgium is a colossal military disaster."
"我们还须准备好 承受接踵而至的打击 ..."
"We must expect another blow to be struck almost immediately."
"我们将战斗到底"
"We shall go on to the end."
"我们将在法国领土上作战"
"We shall fight in France."
"我们将在海洋中作战 ..."
"We shall fight on the seas and oceans."
"本地男孩 乔治·米尔斯 年仅17岁 敦刻尔克的救人英雄"
"我们将以越来越大的信心和越来越强的力量在空中作战 ..."
"We shall fight with growing confidence and growing strength in the air."
"我们将不惜一切代价 保卫本土"
"We shall defend our island whatever the cost..."
什么?!
What?
"我们将不惜一切代价 保卫本土"
"We shall defend our island whatever the cost may be."
"我们将在滩头作战"
"We shall fight on the beaches."
"我们将在敌人的登陆地作战 ..."
"We shall fight on the landing grounds."
"我们将在田间作战 在街头作战 ..."
"We shall fight in the fields and in the streets."
"我们将在山区作战 ..."
"We shall fight in the hills."
"决不投降 ..."
"We shall never surrender."
"即便全岛或本土的大部沦为敌占
"And even if this island or a large part of it"
全体民众饥寒交迫 ..."
"were subjugated and staring,"
"我们海外的帝国子民们"
"then our Empire beyond the seas, armed and guarded by the British Fleet,"
"将在大英舰队的武装和保护下 继续战斗 ..."
"would carry on the struggle"
"一直到天意注定之时 ..."
"until, in God's good time,"
"新的世界 将挺身而出"
"the New World, with all its power and might,"
"倾其全力 拯救旧世界 解放旧世界"
"steps forth to the rescue and the liberation of the old."